Michael Lewis

513-254-1822 | michaellewis1689@outlook.com | Xenia, OH 45385 https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-lewis-74b6143/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am an expert web developer with over 15 years of experience building high quality and performant websites following mobile-first, component-based design and agile development methodologies. I have a certification from Acquia for Drupal development, and my work on City of Hope has won an award. I've worked with teams of various sizes in various roles, all the way up to team lead. I am fully set up to work remotely but am willing to relocate if necessary. I'm looking for an opportunities to lead web development teams, use emerging technologies like AI, and spec into data engineering

EXPERIENCE

Technology Specialist, VML (via TekSystems)

November, 2021 - Present

- Built a brand new website with a fresh design, migration of data, and Apache solr based search for City of Hope website, winning the 2022 <u>eHealthcare Alliance Platinum award</u> for Best Site Design for a Hospital with 200-399 Beds.
- Lead the development team that launched a redesign of Lutron's luxury website with new components, a Content Hub, and an Image gallery to showcase projects and designers that utilize their products.
- Developed an ETL pipeline DAG using Google Cloud Composer to facilitate the migration of CRM data from Salesforce to Braze for Wendy's.
- Rebuilt the MyFembree website for Pfizer with a fresh mobile-first design and improved sitemap to help patients find information about how MyFembree can treat their symptoms and talk to their doctor about whether it is right for them.

Senior Drupal Developer, NLRB (via Puyenpa)

May, 2020 - Nov 2021

- Took over the project lead of a redesign and migration project that was 6 months behind schedule and saw the completion of the project on-time by the original deadline.
 Objectives included completing a migration from Drupal 7 to Drupal 8, completing a re-theme, completing implementation of single sign-on, and other features
- Solved DevOps problems that were plaguing the development process
- Maintained compliance of the website with the high security standards that all federal computer systems must adhere to.
- Solved website performance problems.
- Developed a series of Spanish language translated pages
- Developed website features to enable improved user experience for those seeking to download records from the large volume of case history that was made available through the site.

Senior Drupal Developer, Duo Consulting

January 2017 – April 2020

 Built the new website for Freeborn & Peters LLP that involved a migration from Drupal 7 to Drupal 8

- Built an online point of sale for Chicago Botanic Garden
- Maintained Drupal websites for Bosch, Bracewell LLP, Kettering University and others.

Senior Drupal Developer, TQINet/The Beracha Foundation July 2008 – December, 2016

- Developed an online e-commerce system for WCSG Radio in Cornerstone, Michigan to drive their bi-annual pledge drives.
- Built numerous websites for various non-profit organizations and missionaries to facilitate engaging their donors to support their work.
- API and ETL integrations of data into the Etapestry CRM

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts, Management Information Systems

May, 2006

Cedarville, University

SKILLS

Drupal, Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SASS, Node.js, React, Python, Google Cloud Platform, Acquia, Pantheon, Docker, DNS, SSL, CDN, Github Actions, Microsoft Azure, Atlassian (JIRA/Bitbucket), Figma, Bootstrap, Twig, Tailwind

AWARDS/RECOGNITIONS/VOLUNTEER WORK - (OPTIONAL)

- 2022 <u>eHealthcare Alliance Platinum award for Best Site Design for a Hospital with</u>
 200-399 Beds.
- Acquia Certified Drupal Developer.

April, 2018

- Sunday School Teacher
- Soccer Coach
- Amateur Musician